David King

Software Developer

Location: Mechanicsburg, PA
Email: dkingofpa@gmail.com
Web: http://www.dkingofpa.com

Summary

I'm a self-starter with the proven ability to self-manage. Over 12 years experience as a details oriented software developer and consultant with a track record of delivering projects. I believe in consistency, process, quality tools and being a considerate developer. I also spent a few years teaching and coaching in the public school system at the high school level.

Skills & Expertise

Self-management, Java, Javascript, Drupal, PHP, CSS, SQL, Web Development, Git, SVN, JetBrains tools

Certifications

MCD - Integration and API Associate

MuleSoft License b0ec2fc6-a389-3ba3-a021-9befa459b0d3 November 2016 – November 2018

Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform 1.4 $\,$ May 2004

Work History

Senior Consultant

xforty technologies April 2010 - Present

- Worked with clients to identify project requirements and define scope.
- Provided sales team and clients with project estimates.
- Implemented specifications using various technologies based on client needs.
- Provided ongoing support and maintenance to clients.

Example Projects:

Custom business intelligence application for large university

March 2016 to November 2016

Technology: Java, Javascript (Ext JS), Oracle, Cognos BI

Enhanced existing custom reporting application by adding scheduled reports and a batching process for running of scheduled reports. This provided the customer:

- 1. Greater flexibility and customization of report delivery options.
- 2. Reduction in the number of steps required to run reports for recurring data needs.
- 3. Improved report performance through reducing wait times to run reports.

Intranet/extranet for one of the country's leading defense contractors March 2014 to November 2014

Technology: Drupal, PHP, JMS (RabbitMQ), custom modules for content synchronization

This wide-reaching Drupal intranet project supports 110,000+ active authenticated users across the globe. Implemented the content synchronization between the intranet and extranet while also allowing users to specify the confidentiality of the content.

During the project, I was able to contribute numerous patches back to the Drupal community:

https://www.drupal.org/node/2236229

https://www.drupal.org/node/2302575

https://www.drupal.org/node/2302561

https://www.drupal.org/node/2300301

https://www.drupal.org/node/2275773

https://www.drupal.org/node/2276507

FTC COPPA Compliance for large media corporation

September 2013 to October 2013 Technology: Drupal, PHP, OAuth

https://www.xforty.com/success_stories/coppa-compliance

Customer's Drupal web site and iOS mobile application were required to be COPPA Compliant by the FTC. Failure to meet compliance would result in heavy fines. Any functionality in the software (including certain submitted forms and games) that collected individually identifiable information about a child under the age of 13 would first require verifiable parental consent.

Web sites

April 2010 to Present

Technology: Drupal, PHP, Javascript, CSS

Completed various site builds for customers. Typically involved providing an estimate for the statement of work and then working on the project until the site was delivered to the customer.

9-12th grade Business Education Teacher (long-term sub)

Bermudian Springs School District November 2007 – June 2009

Classes: Business Survey, Word Processing, Microsoft Office, and Multimedia (web dev)

JV Girls Basketball Coach

October 2006 to July 2009

8th Grade Football Coach

May 2008 to April 2009

Graduate Assistant - Dept. of Teacher Education

Shippensburg University May 2006 – December 2006

Software Consultant

Tangeis, LLC February 2006 – April 2006

Software Developer

Perfect Order, Inc (CommNav, Versatile) June 1999 – July 2005

- Developed web applications for core products.
- Maintained internal business critical software included the full requirements gathering, programming, testing, and deployment cycle.
- Developed custom websites and intranets for clients.

Independent Coursework

Dale Carnegie course graduate January 2006

Education

Master of Education in Curriculum and Instruction, 2008 K-12 Business/Computers/Info Tech teacher certification, 2007 Shippensburg University, Shippensburg, PA

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science, 1999Gettysburg College, Gettysburg, PA
Departmental Honors
Cum Laude

Interests

Apple technology, process, clean coding, DX, Maker culture, bonsai, Penn State athletics, Syracuse basketball.